A Guide to the Correspondence and Subject Files of the Librarian of Virginia, 1832-2024 Jan
Library of Virginia
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1827-2007.
  - 1979 (Accession 32336)., 1.25 cu. ft. (4 boxes)
    - Virginia: Health, Dept. of - Madison College, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Virginia: Management Analysis and Systems Development, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Virginia: Mental Hygiene and Hospitals - Property Records and Insurance, 1979. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Virginia: Purchase and Supply - Virginia State College, 1979. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - W; Y, 1979. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Research notes, Church Records in the VSLA, ca. 1979. (Box 4)
  - 1981-1982 (Accession 33057)., 1.35 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
    This collection contains the correspondence of State Librarian, Donald R. Haynes, and Director of Administrative Service, Nolan T. Yelich. Correspondents include but are not limited to; state agencies, donors, associations, universities, public libraries, and the Virginia Historical Society. Topics discussed are; "Cavaliers and Pioneers" Project, Virginia State Library publications, library security, collections and genealogy. Included are; mass mailings, letters, memoranda, and invitations. Box 1 folder 21 contains a brightly illustrated letter of thanks and congratulations from author Tom Wolfe.
    Arranged chronologically, thereunder alphabetically by folder title.
    - A, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - B, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - C, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - D, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - E-G, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - H, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - I, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - J-L, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - M, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - N-P, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - R-T, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - U, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - V, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Virginia: Accounts, Dept. of - Employment Commission, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Virginia: General Services, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Virginia: Governor's Office, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Virginia: Highways and Transportation - Museum of Fine Arts, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Virginia: Planning and Budget, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Virginia: Purchase and Supply - Training, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Virginia: Telecommunications - William and Mary, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - W, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - A, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - B, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - C, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - D, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - F, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - G, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - H, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - I, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - J-L, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - M, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - N, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - O-R, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - S-V, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Virginia: Accounts, Dept. of - General Services, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Virginia: Governor's Office, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Virginia: Joint Legislation Audit Review Commission - Retirement Systems, 1982. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Virginia: Secretary of the Commonwealth - Secretary of Education, 1982. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Virginia: Telecommunications - Virginia State University, 1982. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - W, 1982. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1985-2000 (Accession 44436)., .45 cu. ft. (1 box)
    This collection contains the correspondence of State Librarian, Ella Gaines Yates and Nolan T. Yelich. Correspondents include but are not limited to; state and federal agencies, employees, museums, and libraries. Included are; agenda, minutes, reports, letters, and memorandums.
    Arranged chronologically, thereunder alphabetically.
    - 1985. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1986. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1987. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1990. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1991. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Records Center 1993. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Research and Information Services 1993. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Planning and Future Direction of the Library of Virginia 1999. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 2000. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1987-1994 (Accession 34710)., 6 cu. ft. (6 boxes)
    This collection contains the correspondence of State Librarian, Dr. John C. Tyson, along with minimal material from the previous State Librarian, Ella Gaines Yates. This collection also contains correspondence from State Archivist, Louis Manarin and Assistant State Librarian, Nolan T. Yelich. Correspondents include but are not limited to; state and federal agencies, donors, employees, museums, and library associations. Topics discussed are; replevin, funding, budgets, grant programs and services. Included are; newsletters, reports, letters, and memorandums.
    This collection also contains information on the creation of a state wide network of library catalog databases, documentation includes; journal articles, bibliographic records, adaptation on MARC, studies on library automation, and newsletters from the National Commission on Libraries and Information Services. There is also correspondence related to the visit by Vice President Albert Gore during the Governor's Conference on Economic Development. Dr. Tyson's tenure as state librarian brought with it a commitment to African-American issues in the library field, education and throughout the state in general.
    Box one contains general correspondence which is arranged chronologically, the remainder are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - 1987-1990. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1991 Jan-July. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1991 Aug-Sept. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1991 Oct-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1992 Jan-Mar. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1992 Apr-June. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1992 July-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1993 Jan-Feb. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1993 Mar-Apr. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1993 May. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1993 June-July. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1993 Aug-Sept. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1993 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1993 Nov. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1994 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1994 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1994 Mar; Dec. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Undated. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Accounting Audit Response, 1992. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Administrative Cabinet, 1991-1992. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Administrative Cabinet: Meeting, 1989-1994. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Administrative Cabinet: Meeting, 1992. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Administrative Law Appendix, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Agency Procurement Request, 1987. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - American Library Association: Black Caucus, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Americans with Disabilities Act Regulations, 1991-1992. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Annual Reports, 1987 June 30. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Annual Reports, 1990 June 30. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Annual Report, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Aparteid, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Archives, 1992. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Archives: Acquisitions, 1989-1992. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Archives: Administrative, 1992. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Archives: Alkaline Paper, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Archives: Archivist Classification, 1992. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Archives: Conservation - Circuit Court, 1989-1992. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Archives: Conservation - Public Works, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Archives: General Library Committee, 1987. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Archives: Inventory, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Archives: Mental Health, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Archives: Microfilm, 1992. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Archives: NARA, 1992. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Archives: New Library Building, 1992. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Archives: Replevin - Middlesex and Isle of Wight County, 1991-1993. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Archives: State Records Center, 1989-1993. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Archives: State Universities, 1991-1992. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Archives: T.T. Perry Collection, Undated. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Asbestos Report, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Association of College and Research Libraries, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Attorney General, 1989-1991. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Attorney General: Replevin, 1991-1992. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Attorney General: SOLINET, 1993. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Audit, 1989. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Audit, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Audit, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Audit: Internal, 1990-1991. (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Bill of Rights Tour, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Blue Ridge Regional Library, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Budget, 1983-1986. (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Budget, 1990-1992. (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Budget, 1992-1994. (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Budget, 1993. (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Budget, 1994. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Budget: Harris, Ann, 1990-1991. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Budget Reduction, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Budget Reduction (1 of 2), 1992-1993. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Budget Reduction (2 of 2), 1992-1993. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Budget Reduction, 1994-1996. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Building Committee, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Bsiness Council of Effective Literacy, 1991. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Census, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Chesterfield County Public Library, 1990-1991. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Collections Development Workshop, 1993 June 17. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Collections Repair Policy, 1991. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Colleges and Universities, 1988-1993. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Community Learning Week (Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.), 1992-1993. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Congratulations, 1991-1992. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Continuing Education, 1993. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Consultant: Stem, Al, 1993. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Conultant: W.M. Pierce and Associates, 1991. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Contracts: Automation, 1990-1991. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Cooperative Continuing Education, 1991. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence: Virginia Cavalcade, 1991. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Council on Information Management: Networking, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Critical Issues: Virginia Libraries, 1993 June. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Depository Library Directory, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Donations, 1991-1994. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Economic Development, 1993. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Education, Secretary of, 1991-1993. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Employees: Hartman, Elaine, 1992-1993. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Employees: Kneebone, John, 1993. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Employees: Treadway, Sandra, 1993-1994. (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Employees: Wilson, Ashby, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Employees: Yelich, Nolan, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Executive Mansion, 1990-1991. (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Exhibits, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Fauquier County Public Library, 1991. (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Film Collection: Disposition/Patron Petitions, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Financial Records: Decentralization, 1991-1993. (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - First Freedom Center, 1992; undated. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Friends of the Archives, 1991-1993. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Friends of Virginia Libraries, 1991-1993. (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - General Services, 1991. (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - George Mason: Film, 1991. (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Gillette Papers, 1993. (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Governor's Conference on Library and Information Services, 1990-1991. (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Governor's Symposisium o Virginia's Economic and Budget Outlook, 1992 Nov 13. (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Grants, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Grants: Conservation, 1994. (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Grants: Grant-In-Aid, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Grants: Grant-In-Aid (1 of 2), 1991. (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Grants: Grant-In-Aid (2 of 2), 1991. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Grants: Library Services and Construction Act - Annual Report, 1991. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Grants: Library Services and Construction Act - Annual Report, 1992. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Grants: Library Services and Construction Act - Correspondence, 1990-1991. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Grants: Library Services and Construction Act - Long Range Program, 1991-1995. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Grants: Library Services and Construction Act - Rewards (1 of 3), 1991. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Grants: Library Services and Construction Act - Rewards (2 of 3), 1991. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Grants: Library Services and Construction Act - Rewards (3 of 3), 1991. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Grants: State-Aid, 1991. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Grants: State-Aid Formula, 1991. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Graphs: Funding, 1992-1993. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - House of Delegates, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Illinios Library Computer Systems Office, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Inventory: Archives Stacks, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Joint Legislation Audit Review Commission, 1992-1993. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Land Office Lawsuit, 1991. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Legislation, 1991. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Legislative Petitions Project, 1972-1981. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Library Dedication: Arlington County, 1992 Dec 12. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Library Dedication: Chesterfield County, 1993 May 19. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - library Development, 1990-1992. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Library Development, 1992-1996. (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Library Development and Networking Division, 1992-1994. (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Library Services and Construction Act, 1992. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Library Services and Construction Act, 1993. (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Local Government Commission, 1990-1992. (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Lonesome Pine Regional Library, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Meetings: Public Library Directors, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Meetings: State Document Libraries, 1991. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Minority Business Enterprises, 1990-1992. (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Minutes: Executive Staff Meetings, 1985-1986. (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Museums: Black History Cultural Center, 1991-1992. (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Museums: Edgar Allan Poe, 1990-1993. (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Museums: Virginia Historial Society, 1990-1991. (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Net Lender Reimbursement, 1993. (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Networking (1 of 2), 1979-1984. (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Networking (2 of 2), 1979-1984. (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Networking, 1980-1984. (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Networking (1 of 2), 1981-1984. (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Networking (2 of 2), 1981-1984. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Networking, 1983-1984. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Networking: Commission Study (1 of 2), 1979-1982. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Networking: Commission Study (2 of 2), 1979-1982. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Newport News, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Newsletter: NAGARA, 1992. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - OCLC, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Old Dominion University, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Orange County, 1988. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Personnel, Dept. of, 1989-1991. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Procedures for Operations: Signed, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Publications, 1990-1991. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Public Library Directors, 1992. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Public Library Director's Forum, 1990 Dec. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Public Library Issues Forum, 1992 July 19-20. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Public Records Advisory Council, 1986-1994. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Public Records: Decentralization - Universities, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Recomendations, 1991-1992. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Records Management Memorandums, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Recycling, 1990-1991. (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Research Libraries Information Network, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Rockbridge Area Participants for Information Delivery, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Signage: Highway, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Snowbird Leadership Institute, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Society of American Archivists, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Southeastern Library Association, 1991-1993. (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - southeastern Library Network: Correspondence, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Southeastern Library Network: Nominating Committee (1 of 2), 1992. (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Southestern Library Network: Nominating Committee (2 of 2), 1992. (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Speaking Engagements, 1991-1994. (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Speaking Engagements: Medical Library Association, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Staff Workshop Survey, Undated. (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - State Library Building Functional Analysis, 1987. (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - State Networking Users Advisory, 1991-1992. (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - State Records Center, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Study: Library Construction and Renovation, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Summer Reading Program, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Task Force: Critical Issues, 1993. (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Thanks You Letters: Patrons, 1991-1994. (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Thank You Letters: Dr. Tyson, 1991-1994. (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Thomas Jefferson Celebration (200th Birthday), 1993 Apr 13. (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Tidewater Library Directors Committee, 1990-1991. (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Timesheet, 1992. (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Training: Performax, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1980-1981. (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1981-1982. (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1982-1983. (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1983-1984. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1984-1985. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1985-1987. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1991 July. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1991 Oct-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1993 Jan-Mar. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Vice President: Gore, Albert, 1993. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Library Association, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Virginia State Library and Archives: Administrative Cabinet Meeting, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Virginia State Library and Archives: Administrative Cabinet Meeting, 1990-1991. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Virginia State Library and Archives: Affirmative Action Plan, 1993. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Virginia State Library and Archives: Building Crisis, 1987. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Visually Handicapped, 1989-1990. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Volunteerism, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - 1994 (Accession 41207)., 1 cu. ft. (1 box)
    This collection contains the correspondence of State Librarian, Dr. John C. Tyson. Correspondents include but are not limited to; state and federal agencies, donors, and library associations. Topics discussed are; Virginia State Library publications, collections and services. Included are; reports, letters, memorandums, and invitations.
    Arranged using an internal filing system, grouped by corresondents or subjects.
    - Reference Files, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Governor's Office, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - General Assembly, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Secretary of Education, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Higher Education Council, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Attorney General, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Council on Information Management, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Department of General Services, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Department of Information Technology, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Department of Planning and Budget, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Department of Personnel and Training, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Other State Agencies, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Other States, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Congress, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Federal Agencies - Miscellaneous, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Finance and Administrative Services Division, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Library Development and Networking Division, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Publications and Education Services, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Librarian of Virginia and Staff, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Center of the Book, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Foundation Development Office, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Archives and Records Division, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - General Library Division, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Annual Reports, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Direct Constituent Correspondence, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Locality Correspondence, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Freedom of Information Act, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Sole Source Requests, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Board Minutes, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Agendas and Supporting Documentation, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence with Board Members, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Board Member Personal Correspondence, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - State Historical Records Advisory Board, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Virginia Heritage Stewardship Coordinating Council, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Invitations, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - American Library Association, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Chief Officers of State Library Agencies, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Virginia Library Association, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Virginia Public Library Directors Association, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Southeastern Library Network (Solinet), 1994. (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Virginia Genealogical Society, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - 1995 (Accession 41208)., 2 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
    This collection contains the correspondence of State Librarian, Nolan T. Yelich. Correspondents include but are not limited to; state and federal agencies, donors, and associations. Topics discussed are; Virginia State Library publications, collections and services. Included are; reports, letters, memorandums, and invitations.
    - Governor's Office, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Governor's Office, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - General Assembly, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Secretary of Education, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Attorney General, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Council on Information Management, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Department of General Services, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Department of Planning and Budget, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Department of Personnel and Training, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Other State Agencies, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Other States, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Congress, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Institute for Museums and Library Services, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - National Commission on Librarians Information Sciences, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Library of Congress, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Federal Agencies, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Archival and Information Science, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Finance and Administrative Services Division, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Library Development and Networking Division, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Publications and Educational Services, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Records Management and Imaging Services, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Librarian of Virginia and Staff, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Center for the Book, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Foundation Development Office, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Archives and Records Division, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - General Library Division, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Annual Reports, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Accomplishments Report, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Direct Constituent Correspondence (A-E), 1995. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Direct Constituent Correspondence (F-M), 1995. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Direct Constituent Correspondence (N-S), 1995. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Direct Constituent Correspondence (T-Z), 1995. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Locality Correspondence (A-E), 1995. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Locality Correspondence (F-M), 1995. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Locality Correspondence (N-S), 1995. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Locality Correspondence (T-Z), 1995. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Sole Source Requests, 1995. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Strategic Management Plan, 1995. (Box 2, Folder 6)